Hi there!
In this video, we'll explain the value of
data and how it impacts your projects.
We'll also cover how you'll use data
to communicate with stakeholders.
Data is a big business.
There are 2.5 quintillion bytes
of data created each day.
That's a lot of data and
a lot of information!
Let's start by talking about what data is.
Data is a collection of facts or
information,
and through data analysis, you'll learn
how to use data to draw conclusions and
make predictions and decisions.
We use data daily to help us make
decisions and improve performance.
For example, my friend is a runner who
participates in annual five-kilometer and
ten-kilometer runs.
When she's training for a run,
she uses the data on her GPS watch
to measure her time and distance.
She can even calculate her pace by
measuring the minutes-per-kilometer.
She uses the minutes-per-kilometer data
to track her performance over time so
that she can focus on improving for
the future.
Similarly, companies use data and
data analysis to improve and
bring value to their organization
in a variety of ways.
For example, companies source
data on customer behavior and
customer demand to provide better
services and create new products.
Netflix is a great example of a company
that uses data intelligence to predict
what customers want.
By observing data points surrounding types
of genres, ratings, and number of repeated
viewings, Netflix recommends TV shows
that they believe customers might like,
therefore improving
the customer's viewing experience.
In the same way, as a project manager,
you can use data daily to make
better decisions, solve problems,
understand performance, improve processes,
and understand your users.
Let's examine how these
benefits can impact a project.
Let's talk about how this can play out in
our Plant Pals project at Office Green.
If you have the data on
customer buying patterns and
identify that your best-selling
products are all tropical plants,
you'll be able to make better decisions
when placing new plant orders with your
supplier.
You'll also be able to better
understand your users and
their preferences to improve
your offerings and performance.
Another daily benefit of data within your
project team is the opportunity to improve
processes.
If you have the data from your project
tracker of the number of tasks completed,
the number of escalations, or
the number of issues that come up
surrounding an internal process,
you'll be able to deduce where
the majority of issues are stemming from.
This data will help inform your decision
on where to focus your attention to
improve the process.
While these are simple examples,
through critical analysis,
application, and execution,
data becomes a powerful tool to guide
any project in the right direction.
Coming up, we'll discuss the types of
project data you can use to do just that.